Guide to the George Ivask Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence
  - INCOMING
    - Odarchenko, IUrii, 1952-54 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimrovna, 1952-61 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Otsup, Nikolai, [1951-58] (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Poplavskii, Boris IUlianovich, 1930-[32] (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Remizov, Aleksei, 1951-57 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Shteiger, Anatolii, 1937-41 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Stepun, Fedor Avgustovich, 1955-58 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Ul'berg, A.
      Related Materials
      See: Shteiger, Anatolii
    - Veidle, Mariia Veidle, V., 1953-63, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
    - Zaitsev, Boris, 1954-61 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Zlobin, Vladimir, 1952-55 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - THIRD PARTY
    - TSvetaeva, Marina, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Veidle, V., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - Unidentified correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Writings
  - ARTICLES
    - Gershel'man, Karl Karlovich
      - "'Bunt' Ivana Karamazova", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - "Dostoevskii. 'Zapiski iz podpol'ia", [1943?] (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - "Esteticheskoe sozertsanie i bezsmertie", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - "O bessmertii", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - "Ob igre", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - "TSarstvo Bozhie vne nas", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - "Udivlenie", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Ielita-Wilczkowski, Cyril: "O skonchavshemsia... Anatolii Shteigere", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Ivanov, Georgii Vladimirovich: "Mne sluchaino popalas'... zametka", [1957?] (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Ivask, George
      - "K. K. Gershel'man (1899-1951), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - "Oden" (Auden, W. H.), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Odarchenko, IUrii: "Nochnoe svidanie", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Poplavskii, Boris IUlianovich: "Apollon Bezobrazov", 1926-32 (Box 2, Folder 51-54)
    - Remizov, Aleksei
      - "Dusheia", [1954?] (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - "Ermitazhnaia redkost'", 1945-49 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - "O ponimanii", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - "Polodni nochi", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - POETRY
    - Bunin, Ivan Alekseevich: "Peterburg", [1916?] (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Chervinskaia, Lidiia: "Net ne liubi menia", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Eval'd, K.
      See: Kantor, Mikhail L'vovich
    - Gershel'man, Karl Karlovich
      - "A samoe glavnoe" (6 poems), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - "Stikhi", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Gippius, Z. N. (Zinaida Nikolaevna): "Poslednii Krug", [1943?] (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Golovina, Alla Sergeevna: "V izgolov'i", "Vid", "Nachalo stikhov", "Cheshuia", 1953-54 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Ivanov, Georgii Vladimirovich: "Zima idet svoim poriadkom", 1957 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Kantor, Mikhail L'vovich: "[Stikhi]" (seven poems), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Makovskii, Sergei Konstantinovich: "[Stikhi]" (42 poems), [1952?]-60, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Odarchenko, IUrii: "Dva sleptsa," "Lastochki", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimirovna: "Ty govoril", "Vse bylo", 1957, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Otsup, Nikolai: "Iz stikhov opublikovanykh", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Shteiger, Anatolii, baron: "Siniaia rubashka", "Kak zakrichat'", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - TSvetaeva, Marina: "Chuzhoi," "Toska po rodine", 1934, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Zlobin, Vladimir: "[Stikhi]" (7 poems), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Photographs, 1933
  - Efron, Georgii, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Gronskii, Nikolai Pavlovich, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Remizov, Aleksei (individual and group), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Shteiger, Anatolii, baron, [1937?] (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - TSetaeva, Marina, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Miscellaneous papers, 1913-61, n.d.
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1913-61, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 79)